Voituret Félix

Software Engineering

(+33) 6.48.95.75.46 felix.voituret@ismart.fr 25 years old

Eclipse, Jenkins,
SVN, Archiva, SonarQube,
PhantomJS, Weka,
Java, JIRA, Maven,
Crucible, Selenium,
Jetty, UML, JUnit,
AngularJS

ILOG CPLEX, C++,
MATSim, Java, LaTeX,
Operation Research,
PMD, Checkstyle

Python, Perl,
Java, Selenium, C++,
Javascript, AngularJS,
jQuery, HTML, PHP,
PostgreSOL

Firebird

Passionated by computer science since my childhood, i naturally started to study at Université d'Avignon et des Pays de Vaucluse, in software engineering.

After being graduated with a bachelor degree, with a period in UK, i continued with a master's degree. I also worked at the same time in the Avignon research lab as part of my study program.

Work history

Research and Development Engineer

Kware, Aix en provence, France September 2013 - Present (1 year 10 months)

Evolving in a short sized team, i participate to a solution that provides data mining facilities for a marketing institute. Our solution consists in processing market data and more particularly for a given product, to categorize it reference label and extracts document that contains product description over the web in order to perform product coding. I contributed to all software development steps, namely, design, implementation, code optimization, testing, integration and documentation.

Research assistant

Laboratoire de recherche informatique d'Avignon (LIA), Avignon, France June 2011 - July 2013 (2 years 2 months)

As part of my master degree in software engineering, i participated to research for the coupled problem of land use and network design. I designed and implemented a decision support tool that use the multi-agent simulation system MATSim, to relocate set of facility through a transportation network using a huge amount of data from mobility census.

Freelance developer

Worldwide

Performed various mission as freelance developper, such as software development, web application, scripting. Most missions have been done through Freelancer website and my profile can be consulted at the following URL: https://www.freelancer.com/u/Faylixe.htm

Hotliner

CBA Informatique, Avignon, France July 2008 - March 2009 (9 months)

Provided support to customers, assisted them for installing, and using an information system.

French Native

English Full professional proficiency

Education

Université d'Avignon et des Pays de Vaucluse

Master's degree - Software engineering and Business Intelligence 2011 - 2013

Degree obtained with upper second class honours. English certification BULATS obtained with 86 out of 100 score.

University of Birmingham

European exchange semester 2010 - 2011

Semester performed as part of the Erasmus program during my bachelor degree

Université d'Avignon et des Pays de Vaucluse

Bachelor's degree - Computer Science 2008 - 2011

Degree obtained with lower second class honours.

Publication

Decoupling accessibility and automobile mobility in urban areas Transport Research Arena 2014 - #20017

The aim of this article is to see to what extent it is possible to tend to cities where accessibility will be decoupled from the speed of car travel. In this context, as a first step, we simulate different policies of speed regulation and investigate their effects on modal split, distances travelled, and people satisfaction using a multi-agent simulation tool and taking Zurich (Switzerland) as a test case.